// CDL Tanker Vehicle Practice test

questions = [
{
  question: "Side-to-side surge can cause:",
  choices: [
    "Suspension system failure.",
    "Over speeding.",
    "A rollover."
  ],
  correct: "A rollover."
},
{
  question: "What does liquid surge do to handling of a tanker?",
  choices: [
    "Surge raises the wind drag of the truck.",
    "It can move the truck in the direction the liquid waves move.",
    "Surge lets you turn corners tighter."
  ],
  correct: "It can move the truck in the direction the liquid waves move."
},
{
  question: "Hauling liquids in tankers requires special care for two reasons. Tankers are:",
  choices: [
    "Flat",
    "Wide",
    "High"
  ],
  correct: "High"
},
{
  question: "How would you expect a truck with a cargo tank that has baffles to handle on the road?",
  choices: [
    "The truck will seem heavier than it really is.",
    "There will be less front-to-back surge than there is in a tanker without baffles.",
    "The truck will handle the same as a tanker without baffles."
  ],
  correct: "There will be less front-to-back surge than there is in a tanker without baffles."
},
{
  question: "You need to be very careful when driving smooth bore tankers. This is especially true when you are:",
  choices: [
    "Starting or stopping.",
    "Loading and unloading.",
    "Hauling milk or other food products."
  ],
  correct: "Starting or stopping."
},
{
  question: "Empty trucks:",
  choices: [
    "Stop quicker when you use only the emergency or parking brake.",
    "Have better traction when stopping than full trucks.",
    "May require a longer stopping distance than full trucks."
  ],
  correct: "May require a longer stopping distance than full trucks."
},
{
  question: "When you unload the smaller tanks of a tank with bulkheads, be careful to check your:",
  choices: [
    "Distribution of weight.",
    "Air to fuel ratio.",
    "Water content."
  ],
  correct: "Distribution of weight."
},
{
  question: "The best way to take a curve with a tanker is to slow to a safe speed before entering the curve, then as you go through it:",
  choices: [
    "Speed up slightly.",
    "Brake lightly.",
    "Downshift twice."
  ],
  correct: "Speed up slightly."
},
{
  question: "The liquid in a tank with baffles can still have what kind of surge?",
  choices: [
    "Side-to-side",
    "Top-to-bottom",
    "Front-to-back"
  ],
  correct: "Front-to-back"
},
{
  question: "You should be very cautious when driving smooth bore tankers, especially when you are:",
  choices: [
    "Going uphill or downhill.",
    "Starting or stopping.",
    "Driving against the wind."
  ],
  correct: "Starting or stopping."
},
{
  question: "You should know the outage needed for the liquids you carry because:",
  choices: [
    "Some of the heaviest liquids do not need any outage.",
    "Tank baffles are not always legal with outage.",
    "Some liquids expand more than others when they get warm."
  ],
  correct: "Some liquids expand more than others when they get warm."
},
{
  question: "When you load the small tanks of a cargo tank equipped with bulkheads, you should check the:",
  choices: [
    "Water content.",
    "Air to fuel ratio.",
    "Distribution of weight."
  ],
  correct: "Distribution of weight."
},
{
  question: "Baffles in liquid cargo tanks do not usually prevent surge:",
  choices: [
    "Side-to-side",
    "Top-to-bottom",
    "Front-to-back"
  ],
  correct: "Front-to-back"
},
{
  question: "You are driving on a clear night. You must dim your headlights from high to low. You should adjust your speed so that you can stop within:",
  choices: [
    "The distance you will travel in the next 15 seconds.",
    "The distance you can see ahead.",
    "The length of your vehicle."
  ],
  correct: "The distance you can see ahead."
},
{
  question: "When your cargo tank has baffles, what handling effect do you expect?",
  choices: [
    "There will be less side-to-side surge than there is in a tank without baffles.",
    "There will be less front-to-back surge than there is for a tank.",
    "There will be a slower surge than quick surge."
  ],
  correct: "There will be less front-to-back surge than there is for a tank."
},
{
  question: "Hauling liquids in tank vehicles requires special care for two reasons:",
  choices: [
    "Liquid movement.",
    "Extreme weight.",
    "Uneven expansion."
  ],
  correct: "Liquid movement."
},
{
  question: "When should the driver of a tanker that has lost its brakes use a truck escape ramp?",
  choices: [
    "Only if the tank has baffles.",
    "Always.",
    "Never."
  ],
  correct: "Always."
},
{
  question: "You are driving a tanker truck. The front wheels begin to skid. Which of these is most likely to occur?",
  choices: [
    "You will continue in a straight line and keep moving forward no matter how you steer.",
    "Liquid surge will pull the tank from the truck.",
    "The truck will roll over."
  ],
  correct: "You will continue in a straight line and keep moving forward no matter how you steer."
},
{
  question: "An emergency forces you to stop your tanker quickly or crash. You should:",
  choices: [
    "Lock the brakes with the pedal and hold it there.",
    "Use only the emergency brakes.",
    "Use controlled or stab braking."
  ],
  correct: "Use controlled or stab braking."
},
{
  question: "Which of these statements about emergency steering and tankers is true?",
  choices: [
    "A tanker is easier to counter-steer than most vehicles.",
    "Use only the emergency brakes.",
    "You should wrap your thumbs around the steering wheel before starting a quick steering movement."
  ],
  correct: "You should wrap your thumbs around the steering wheel before starting a quick steering movement."
},
{
  question: "Outage means:",
  choices: [
    "Liquid weight.",
    "How fast the liquid tanks drain.",
    "Allowance for expansion of liquid."
  ],
  correct: "Allowance for expansion of liquid."
},
{
  question: "Liquid-tight separators between compartments inside tanks are called:",
  choices: [
    "Bulkheads.",
    "Baffles.",
    "Barriers."
  ],
  correct: "Bulkheads."
},
{
  question: "The amount of liquid to load into a tank depends on:",
  choices: [
    "The amount the liquid will expand in transit.",
    "The legal weight limits.",
    "Both of the above factors."
  ],
  correct: "Both of the above factors."
},
{
  question: "Separators, with openings or holes in them, that are between compartments in a tank are called:",
  choices: [
    "Bulkheads.",
    "Baffles.",
    "Barriers."
  ],
  correct: "Baffles."
},
{
  question: "Which of these statements about stopping distance and speed is true?",
  choices: [
    "You need about two times as much stopping distance at 40 mph as at 20 mph.",
    "Wet roads can double stopping distance at any speed.",
    "Both of the above are true."
  ],
  correct: "Both of the above are true."
}
];